Altay Aydemir

Birth: January 14, 1994 / Turkey

Location: Berlin, Germany

Visa: EU Blue Card (valid until 2023)

Email: altay@aydemir.io

Website: altay.wtf

Summary

I'm a software engineer with 5+ years of experience, mostly focused on the user-facing side of the digital products. I enjoy transforming an idea into something tangible if it's solving a problem I empathize with.

Technical Background

Areas: Media Streaming, Cloud Storage, Blockchain, FinTech

Interests: Functional Programming, Domain-Driven Design, Humane Product Design

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Swift, Kotlin (beginner)

Runtimes and Platforms: NodeJS, Web, iOS, tvOS, Android, LG webOS, Tizen, Roku, Chromecast

Buzzwords: React, React Native, Styled Components, Jest, Storybook, Visual Testing, Express, GraphQL, Webpack, Docker, Fastlane, TravisCI, Apache Kafka

Work Experience

Software Engineer at Klarna (Berlin, Germany) [May 2019 - July 2021]

Senior Engineer at Consumer Deals (01.2020 - 07.2021)

Switched to a product team focusing on Shopping Growth that I built the MVP back in 2019.

On-boarded new hires.

Led the front-end feature development and cross-team integrations.

Senior Engineer at App Client Core (01.2020 - 01.2021)

Got promoted to Senior Engineer and switched to a distributed team (Stockholm, Berlin, Amsterdam) which is responsible for the integrity, performance, security and the release cycle of the consumer application, which is live in 14 countries with average 6M daily active users.

Restructured the localization architecture of the app to support 10 languages with different dialects.

Worked on a package based feature isolation initiative in the monorepo to allow product teams to develop their features in a more safe and standardized way.

Helped new joiners to on-board Klarna App ecosystem, reviewed 300+ pull-requests from 50+ teams.

Did code reviews (Stockholm) and interviews (Berlin) for hiring pipelines.

Altay Aydemir 2

Engineer at Consumer Growth and Loyalty - Marketing Touchpoint Infrastructure (06.2019 - 01.2020)

Integrated native SDKs of the 3rd party analytics and marketing platforms to the consumer facing app.

Developed several loyalty related campaign infrastructures by using Kafka, NodeJS and React.

On-boarded new teams to the ecosystem by organising workshops and tutorials.

Frontend Engineer at Lightcurve GmbH (Berlin, Germany) [Nov 2018 - May 2019]

Worked on the cross-platform Lisk Mobile app, built with React Native.

Implemented Bitcoin support according to BIP49 standard.

Developed native modules by using Swift.

Software Engineer at Putio (Istanbul, Turkey) [Jan 2017 - ∞]

Worked in a small team consisting of three engineers.

Took full responsibility on the client-facing applications of the product.

Maintained and implemented new features to the existing web app.

Designed and built the new landing page.

Built a proof-of-concept iOS app with React Native, then iterated on the v2 with Swift which includes features such as Chromecast and downloading media for offline consumption.

Developed an Apple TV application with Swift, TVML and TVMLJSKit.

Developed web-based Smart TV applications for Samsung Tizen, LG WebOS, AndroidTV and Amazon FireTV platforms.

Developed a Roku application with BrightScript.

Built cross-browser extensions with WebExtensions API.

Automated build and deployment processes by using Fastlane, Jenkins and TravisCI.

Frontend Engineer at Vispera (Istanbul, Turkey) [Sep 2016 - Mar 2017]

Re-designed and structured the front-end layer of the core Rails application.

Built single-page apps for complex data entry and management purposes with React.

Frontend Engineering Intern at Peergust (Istanbul, Turkey) [Mar 2016 - Sep 2016]

Built demo apps and content management panel for testing and marketing purposes of the P2P content delivery network by using React.

Altay Aydemir 3

Education

BSc. Mechanical Engineering, Istanbul Bilgi University. (2012 - 2016)

Graduated in the 2nd place of the department with 2.90 GPA.

Last updated: August 9, 2021